虚幻勇士冒险 S2E3 时间 由özberk özen制作
视频来源：https://youtu.be/tAGH0KgXoeg，中文字幕由熙洛Chincode制作，翻译：jky，Albeta
Hey Odd, do you know where are the others?
嘿 Odd 你知道其他人在哪里吗？
The school is literally empty.
学校简直是空的
Don't worry, I spoke to Jeremy. All of them are waiting for us at the cafe.
别担心 我和Jeremy谈过了 他们都在咖啡馆里等着我们
I still can't believe that we really saved Franz Hopper.
我还是不相信我们真的救了Franz Hopper
Everything's easier now.
现在一切都变得简单了
And Aelita is so happy
而Aelita也很高兴
That's right buddy, luck is on our side
这就对了 伙计 我们还是很幸运的
Well for the first time.
好吧 这是第一次运气这么好
Okay Einstein, at same time, what's our next mission?
好了 爱因斯坦 与此同时 我们的下一个任务是什么？
Your next mission is really simple actually.
你的下一个任务其实很简单
Basically, you'll go back to that big sector and you will destroy it.
基本上 你会回到那个大区 并摧毁它
I've got really weird feelings about this sector, I wonder where its supercomputer is.
我觉得这个区域很奇怪 我想知道它的超级计算机在哪里
Well we'll find out soon enough.
嗯 我们很快就会知道了
That's true and I'm afraid.
这倒是没错 但我很害怕
Hey, how is Franz Hopper feeling?
嘿 Franz Hopper感觉怎么样？
He's Okay, he's at the factory at the moment, working on a new program for the supercomputer
他很好 他现在在工厂里 正在为超级计算机开发一个新程序
Cool, what kind of program is that?
酷 那是什么样的程序？
Marabounta?
行军蚁？
Haha, very funny but no, thanks to the program he's creating, you'll have more life points
哈哈 非常有趣 但不是 得益于他正在创建的程序 你将有更多的生命值
More life points means longer fights and we will complete missions way easier where victories.
更多的生命值意味着更长的战斗时间 我们将更容易完成任务 取得胜利
Also means bye bye XANA as soon as possible.
同时也意味着可以尽快地告别XANA
And all of these thanks to my father.
这些都要感谢我父亲
And your virtualization time will be shorter.
而且你的虚拟化时间会更短
Oh thanks for the reminder by the way,
哦 谢谢你的提醒 顺便说一下
did you know that now we don't have to wait 12 hours to get back to Lyoko?
你知道吗 现在我们不用再等12个小时才能回到Lyoko了
This program will make the waiting time much shorter.
这个程序会让等待的时间大大缩短
Oh no, XANA's attacking.
哦 不 XANA的攻击
Not now.
别现在来啊
Ah, what are those windows?
啊 那些窗口是什么？
Is it the return to the past program?
是回到过去的程序吗？
What's happening?
发生了什么事？
This light, what's happening?
这道光 发生了什么？
Huh, Did you all feel this. Einstein, what was that?
嗯 你们都感觉到了吗 爱因斯坦 那是什么？
It felt like the Return to the Past.
感觉像是回到过去
But-
但是...
But it was red.
但它是红色的
Something's wrong.
有点不对劲
And I don't like it.
而且我不喜欢它
Wait guys, this is more than just a return to the past. Look at the people.
等等 伙计们 这不仅仅是回到过去 看看这些人
They all froze.
他们都停住了
I think you're all missing a question.
我想你们都忽略了一个问题
Why aren't we being affected by this thing too?
为什么我们没有被这个东西影响？
For the very same reason, we're not affected by the normal return to the past.
正是因为同样的情况 我们没有被正常的时间倒转程序所影响
This is no time to drag your feet.
现在不该拖沓了
Let's go, we can't lose more time.
我们走吧 不能再浪费时间了
Father, what happened?
父亲 发生了什么事？
Is everything OK there?
那里一切正常吗？
XANA activated a tower and changed the return to the past program.
XANA激活了一座圆塔 改变了时间倒转的程序
Time has stopped all around the world.
世界各地的时间都停止了
Oh no, this is bad... the nuclear power plants need people to work.
哦 不 这很糟糕......核电站需要有人去工作
This is a disaster!
这是一场灾难
That's true, so hurry up and deactivate this tower.
没错 所以赶紧把这个圆塔锁定了
Hurry, Aelita.
快点 Aelita
I'm on my way, Daddy. Hang on a second, I'm coming.
我在路上了 爸爸 等一下 我就来了
We have to be faster or the nuclear power plants can explode.
我们必须更快 否则核电站会爆炸的
So hurry.
所以快点
I'm going, Daddy. Hang on a second...We're nearly there
我这就去 爸爸 等一下 我们快到了
Transfer Yumi.
传送Yumi
Transfer Aelita.
传送Aelita
Transfer Ulrich.
传送Ulrich
Transfer Odd.
传送Odd
Scanner and Virtualization!
扫描并虚拟化
I've located the tower. It's in the middle of the maze.
我已经找到了那座圆塔 它在迷宫的中间
Go and deactivate it.
去把它锁定吧
Meanwhile, Jeremy, I need your help. We have to fix the return to the past program.
同时 Jeremy 我需要你的帮助 我们必须修复时间倒转的程序
I'm on it.
我正在做
Yo Franzy, we found the tower but there's a little big problem.
哟 Franz 我们找到了圆塔 但有一个不小的问题
Ah... rats!! XANA also attacked the virtual map.
啊......糟糕 XANA也攻击了虚拟地图
I don't know what's happening...Would you mind explaining please?
我不知道发生了什么......你能解释一下吗？
Our blok friends are there to visit us
我们的方文朋友来了
but there's a bigger one in the middle, I never saw anything like this before.
但中间有一只更大的 我以前从未见过这样的东西
It doesn't look friendly, that's for sure.
看起来可以肯定地说 它并不友好
I see, it looks like an alpha blok.
我明白了 它看起来像一个阿尔法方文
It's got more life points than the others. You have to hit it twice.
它的生命值比其他的多 你必须要打它两次
His lasers are distracting me. What's happening?
他的激光让我分心了 发生了什么事？
Ulrich. You will pay for this, Bloks.
Ulrich 你会为此付出代价的 方文
Laser arrows.
激光箭
What happened to the others?
其他人怎么了？
I'm not sure, I don't know but it doesn't affect you.
我不确定 我不知道 但这并不影响你
Come on Aelita, you are our last hope.
来吧Aelita 你是我们最后的希望
You can do it.
你能做到的
Show me what you're made of.
你肯定可以做到
Energy field!
能量球
Well done my angel!
干得漂亮 我的天使
Now go to the Celestial Dome and make the connection.
现在去外域 进行连接
I believe in you, my daughter.
我相信你 我的女儿
First things first, let's deactivate the tower!
首先 让我们锁定圆塔
Tower deactivated.
圆塔锁定了
Well done, sweetheart, now make the connection.
干得好 亲爱的 现在进行连接
Quick hurry up, we can't lose more time.
快点儿 我们不能再浪费时间了
Don't worry, I'm at the Celestial Dome.
别担心 我已经到外域了
I'm on the interface, Daddy. I'm starting.
我打开界面了 爸爸 我开始了
You can do it, Aelita. You can do it.
你能做到的 Aelita 你能做到的
Scyphozoa!
钵水母纲
What? Aelita, get out of there immediately.
什么？Aelita 立即离开那里
Abort the mission.
中止任务
No, we are so close.
不 就快做完了
No way, Aelita, I believe in you.
不要这样 Aelita 我相信你
You can do this.
你可以做到这一点
You're right, I can do this.
你是对的 我可以做到这一点
No more running from the Scyphozoa. It's enough!
不要再逃避钵水母纲了 已经够了
Take this one of, you ugly jellyfish.
吃吃这个 你这个丑陋的水母
I can't believe this, you did it, Aelita.
难以置信 你做到了 Aelita
Well done, sweetheart, I was so afraid and you did it.
干得好 亲爱的 我是如此害怕 而你做到了
Oh now make the connection.
哦 现在把它连接起来
Come on, hurry up!
来吧 快点
Thanks Dad, oh Okay.
谢谢爸爸 哦 好的
The connection was made.
连接成功了
We've fixed the program!
我们已经修复了这个程序
Well we all know what's next.
好了 我们都知道接下来是什么
Return to the past now.
马上时间倒转
But what's this red bubble?
但是这个红色的泡泡是什么？
Don't answer. I've got this covered. I know the answer.
不要回答 我已经把这个问题解决了 我知道答案
With my telepathic powers..my beautiful powers, I'll tell you the answer in no time.
以我的心灵感应能力......我美丽的能力 我很快就能告诉你答案
I see the Light, I know you see it too.
我看到了亮光 我知道你也看到了
The thing you're looking for is called "time stopper" Haha.
你要找的东西叫时间停止器 哈哈
That's it. How did you do it?
就这样吧 你是怎么做到的？
I might have seen it in the screens.
我可能以前在电影里看到过这个名字
But how was XANA capable of doing this?
但XANA怎么有能力做到这一点？
He probably found a way to control time again.
他可能又找到了一个控制时间的方法
Wait, that means that he can do that every time?
等等 这意味着他每次都能这样做？
Thankfully no. I've locked down all the ways to control time.
幸好没有 我已经锁定了所有控制时间的方法
Well, good news for us then.
那么 对我们来说是个好消息了
What will we do now?
我们现在要做什么？
Any ideas?
有什么想法吗？
We will find a way to destroy XANA once and for all.
我们将找到一种方法 一劳永逸地摧毁XANA
I just wonder like I always do.
我现在总是在想这件事
Meanwhile, what is he going to do?
以及 他要做什么呢？
I don't know but we saw it today. It just can't get any worse, can it?
我不知道 但我们今天看到了 它不可能变得更糟糕 不是吗？